SARATH SIVADASAN

Phone: 262-271-6756 (US), 9446470539 (India)
Email - sarathsivadasan.kailas@gmail.com
Alternative Email - sarath.sivadasan1987@gmail.com

Experienced in Object Oriented as well as Web based Analysis, Design and Development. Have 12+ years of experience in developing and leading multiple projects in retail as well as healthcare domain.

KEY SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

NodeJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Angular, React, HLML5, CSS, Java, MS-DOS, PowerShell, MySQL, MSSQL, C++, VC++, MFC

SOURCE CONTROL

GitHub, VSS, Perforce

OTHER TOOLS

Jira, Confluence, ALM, DOORS, Rational Rose, Visio, Rally, Ice Scrum, MS Word, MS Power Point, MS Excel

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR APPLICATION DEVELOPER – GLOBALIZATION PARTNERS (JULY 2019 – TILL NOW)

- Work with Product Managers to understand the requirements on new shopping capabilities.
- Design and develop features for improving shopping capabilities using NodeJS, React, Angular, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Java, Spring boot microservices.
- Analyze production issues and provide immediate fixes.

SENIOR APPLICATION DEVELOPER - BJS WHOLESALE CLUB (AUGUST 2019 - JULY 2021)

- Work with Product Managers to understand the requirements on new shopping capabilities.
- Design and develop features for improving shopping capabilities using NodeJS, Angular, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Java, Spring boot microservices.
- Design, develop and modify the DB2 and MySQL database schema based on software design.
- Design and develop APIs for loading and retrieving large data sets using Dynamo DB.
- Work with third party ecommerce clients like group by, vision web etc. and integrate their solutions.
- Analyze production issues and provide immediate fixes.
- Work in an onshore offshore delivery model to deliver code continuously to meet an aggressive timeline.
- Enforce, ensure and follow HIPAA and PCI compliance throughout the development cycle.
- Work with IT infrastructure team in setting up the environment.

LEAD ENGINEER - GE HEALTHCARE (JUNE 2015 – AUGUST 2019)

- Lead a team of six members and worked on enhancing the service features in ultrasound scanner.
- Developed web framework and services for servicing ultrasound scanners across multiple product lines using NodeJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, jQuery.
- Solutioned migration of logging system in ultrasound scanner software from flat files to MSSQL database.
- Analyzed requirements with core group of ultrasound service engineers and provided engineering solutions.
- Coordinated with global cross functional teams to integrate Service key, remote connectivity through encrypted tunnel, privacy & security related implementations.
- Reviewed and documented requirements, design and test procedures and supported user manual preparation, SOUP preparation.
- Supported global delivery releases for GE ultrasound product line.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER – QUEST GLOBAL (OCTOBER 2014 – MAY 2015)

- Architected and developed a portable DICOM viewer in C++/MFC for viewing medical images.
- Developed tools and provided engineering solutions for analyzing data from scanner applications.
- Developed build and installation scripts and supported integration of the modules to ultrasound scanner.
- Documented requirements, design and test procedures and created wireframes.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER – NETWORK SYSTEMS AND TECHNOLOGIES (APRIL 2010 – SEPTEMBER 2014)

- Designed and architected a web framework and services that intelligently allocates scan studies to radiologists for generating reports.
- Developed a Protocol solution tool that reads protocols and executes them.
- Modified and implemented new UI features for ultrasound workstation.
- Support and maintenance of workstation software.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KERALA

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING CGPA: **7.39**

SKILLS

- Cross-functional team leadership.
- Integration
- Healthcare Domain
- Medical Devices
- Process Improvement

- Excellent Problem Solver
- Troubleshoot and debug issues
- Strong knowledge on data structures
- Agile scrum methodologies
- Strong Oral and Written Communication

MAY 2009